Currently, we are in the introduction phase of
نحن الآن في المرحلة التمهيدية لهذه
this course and I'm sure you are curious about what the course is going to cover.
الدورة التدريبية وأنا متأكد أنكم تشعرون بالفضول بشأن ما سنتناوله فيها.
Let's go over each lesson in the course at
لنستعرض الآن كل درس من دروس الدورة
a high level and what we are going to learn there.
وما سوف نتعلمه فيها.
As you can see, the lessons in the course are going to follow
كما ترون، سوف تتبع الدروس في هذه الدورة
a typical freelancing project journey. Let's get going.
المسار التقليدي لرحلة المشروع الحر. لنكمل.
We'll start with the lesson on sourcing clients,
سنبدأ بالدرس الخاص بإيجاد العملاء،
how and where to find clients to work with.
أي كيف وأين تجد العملاء للعمل معهم.
We'll also do a deeper dive into freelancing platforms and how we can
سوف نأخذ أيضًا فكرة أكثر عمقًا عن منصات العمل الحر وعن كيفية
apply to work on client's projects by sending them a brief expression of interest.
التقدم للعمل على مشاريع العملاء بإرسال رسالة إبداء اهتمام مختصرة.
Then we'll talk about things to discuss with
بعد هذا سوف نتكلم في الأشياء التي يجب مناقشتها
the client before we formally start a project with them,
مع العميل قبل البدء في العمل على المشروع رسميًا،
things like project scope and pricing frameworks.
أشياء مثل نطاق المشروع وهياكل التسعير.
Also any non-disclosure or service agreements that we need to sign.
سوف نتكلم أيضًا عن اتفاقات السرية والخدمة التي سوف نحتاج لتوقيعها.
We'll then talk about strategies to manage projects
بعد هذا سوف نتناول استراتيجيات إدارة المشروع
with the discussion on project management tools like Trello.
مع مناقشة أدوات إدارة المشاريع مثل Trello.
Finally, we'll discuss best practices to formally close
وأخيرًا، سوف نناقش الممارسات المثلى لإنهاء المشاريع
out a project maintaining a good relationship with the client.
رسميًا مع الحفاظ على علاقة طيبة بالعميل.